Mark Hayes

223 Genesee Marquette, MI 49855 T (906) 322-3097 mark.m.hayes1@gmail.com

Profile

I am a strategic and innovative thinker with 13 years of business development and management experience and 3 years of self-education in web design and development. I've completed 4 freelance projects in the past year. My strengths include creativity, tenacity, and resourcefulness.

Wed Development

Freelance Developer Marquette, MI April 2016-Present

My freelance work has focused on self-education in all aspects of web development front and back end, with the underlying goal of becoming a technical project manager. Over the past 3 years I have spent my free time building knowledge in HTML5, CSS, and JavaScript. I've developed professional experience with several tools, libraries, and software packages required for modern web development including: Git and GitHub, NodeJS and Gulp, Wordpress, Square, and Sketch. I've recently started investigating ReactJS.

Poets Pet Parlor Marquette, MI August 2016

Developer

Poets Pet Parlor was my first site. I build the site using HTML5, and CSS and hosted through GitHub Pages. At the client's request, I also integrated live Instagram feed "widget" that updates every 10 minutes. The site is fully responsive and optimized for mobile.

Panara Imports Marquette, MI January 2017

Designer and Developer

I designed and built Panara Imports, which really gave me a great understanding of project management and client relationship from start to finish. I built a focused and minimal site to generate online traffic and bring business to the store, with plans for site expansion towards the end of 2017 into e-commerce through Square.

Women's Center Marquette, MI September 2017

Designer and Developer

The Women's Center project was the largest project I've done and involved a full redesign, and content management system(CMS) and hosting transfer. I created the design and used Wordpress as the CMS to allow for client control and adjustments in the future. I worked directly with the client throughout the process to ensure that content and functionality were correct and that design fit the tone of their brand and mission.

Derouin's Auto Shop Marquette, MI April 2018

Designer and Developer

Derouin's Auto Shop was my first paid job. The client was simply looking for a fresh look and to make the site mobile friendly. I created the design and built the site on Wordpress, allowing the client to make updates and perform common maintenance tasks.

Mark Hayes

223 Genesee
Marquette, MI 49855
T (906) 322-3097
mark.m.hayes1@gmail.com

Professional Experience

Verizon Wireless Marquette, MI April 2016-Present

Solutions Specialist

- Sales associate with direct customer interface. Providing tech support and trouble shooting for customer devices.
- Within 6 months of hiring, became the top sales rep in my store and top 20% of the Great Lakes Central District.
- Leader in new accounts and strategic phone adds for the Great Lakes Central District November and December 2017.

Red Frog Events Chicago, IL 2012-2016

Project Manager

- Managed and planned 30,000+ person events across the United States and around the world including Firefly Music Festival and Warrior Dash
- Negotiated contracts to establish long-term partnerships with major clients and vendors, including Game Face Media, Waste Management, and A-list Parking.
- Developed business plan for new regional event, Candy Cane Express, inaugural event garnered \$40,000 profit.
- Tasked with conceiving large-scale business ventures and events, where gross profit were to exceed 1 million in sales.
- Managed customer research and outreach for EventSprout online ticketing platform.

LSSU Recreation Center Sault Ste. Marie, MI 2008-2012

Facility Supervisor

- Supervised campus recreation facility utilized by entire student body and public.
- Wrote and implemented employee handbook in order to standardize best practices.
- Created positive data driven changes by analyzing visitor surveys and conducting user experience interviews.
- Administered program funding for campus organizations.

Starbucks Coffee Onalaska, WI 2006-2008

Store Manager

 Managed all store operations including customer and partner relations, employee scheduling, payroll and budgeting for 12 employees, 1 assistant manager and over \$60,000 in annual sales.

GKC and Carmike Cinema Marquette, MI 1999-2006 General Manager

- Oversaw all operations for 18-screen theater.
- Managed payroll, inventory and sales tracking for over \$1 million in annual sales. Supervised and instructed six assistant managers and 40+ employees.

Mark Hayes

223 Genesee Marquette, MI 49855 T (906) 322-3097 mark.m.hayes1@gmail.com

Education

LAKE SUPERIOR STATE UNIVERSITY, 01/08 - 05/12

Bachelor of Science in Parks and Recreation

GPA 3.89 - Dean's list, graduated Alpha Chi National Honors Society

Skills

Languages:

HTML5 (3 years) CSS (3 years) SASS (1 year) PHP (1 year) JavaScript (1 year) **Libraries and Tools:**

Gulp (1 year) GitHub (2 years) Git (2 years) Wordpress (1 year) ReactJS (3 months) **Applications:**

Terminal (3 years) macOS (5 years) Sublime Text (3 years) Sketch (3 years)

References

Sarah Doyle

General Manager Verizon Wireless sarahanndoyle@yahoo.com (906) 399-1709 Shana Kleinschmidt

Owner/Operator Poets Pet Parlor spavegli@gmail.com (906) 362-0374

Bugsy Sailor Owner/Operator U.P. Supply Company hello@bugsy.me (906) 395-7570 Tom Kita
Wizard of Web
Red Frog Events
tomkita00@gmail.com

(708) 846-9469

Beth Casady Executive Director Women's Center bcasady@miuplink.com

(906) 869-1237

Ashley Siebels

Art Director
Ladders
heyo@ashleysiebels.com

(612) 986-2585